MARYIA PAKLONSKAYA

- Vilnius, Lithuania
 +370 668 52134 (Phone calls)
- mariapoklonskaya@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/maryia-paklonskaya •

PRODUCT OWNER / PRODUCT MANAGER

Product Owner with almost 5 years of experience in product management and software development. Being really proud that once I migrated 350,000 vehicles to the new unified library of vehicle types (75 types in 5 categories created by me from scratch) and that I created a referral program for the dog's smart collar application which generates real money. Love creating products people (and dogs \bigcirc) love.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTEQ • Vilnius, Lithuania • Senior Business Analyst (Product Owner) • (June 2022 – now)

Softeq is a full-stack development company, offering expert consulting with focus on startups.

Huge team of more than 40 helped to grow the business of **smart collars for dogs**. Delivered requirements for both the physical product (collars) and SaaS mobile application, which tracks dogs' location and controls that the pet is inside the specified virtual fence via GPS.

Notable accomplishments:

- Delivered the referral program to the application ('user A' shares a personal link 'user B' buys product with a discount). With the feature being delivered in September, it managed to gather \$XX,000 in monthly sales. Even more revenue was received during the Holidays (Black Friday, Christmas promos etc.);
- Researched (both best market solutions and competitors) and delivered the **Family membership** feature with customer satisfaction of the feature 4.4 out of 5 and increase of the NPS.

GURTAM • Vilnius, Lithuania • Growth Product Manager (Onboarding) • (January 2022–June 2022)

Created hypotheses to improve the Onboarding process to our partners and their customers.

- Proved 9 of 10 hypotheses as valid based on interviews with the partners.
- Conducted more than 20 interviews with partners around the world in a month.

Owned key metrics for the Onboarding track (everything related to the conversion from filling out the form on website - to getting the demo platform access - to becoming a partner/customer of the partner) and all activities within those steps. Set goals for the quarter, month and sprint.

GURTAM • Minsk, Belarus & Vilnius, Lithuania • Product Owner • (March 2020 – January 2022)

Lead one of the agile scrum teams (up to 12 team members) of the core company product – Wialon (the telematics and fleet management SaaS-based suite of applications: Wialon Hosting, Wialon CMS Manager, Logistics) with more than 3 million active vehicles. Owned Vision of the stream and delivered it to the team.

Notable accomplishments:

- **Delivered new charts module** (solution for visualization of vehicle data to identify faults or vehicle misuse) with new features several y-axis, data comparison between 2 dots, simulations unit tracing on the map and on the chart. Conducted market and competitors researches, analysis of the feedback in all internal systems, analytics of the current usage of the charts features;
- Improved the fleet dashboard: added the mileage card, improved the visualization of the cards, added fuel consumption card. 8 feedback out of 10 were positive;
- Added new login options to the platform (via Google or via enterprise SSO solution Auth0). Login via Google rapidly became one of the most frequent login method;

• Participated in building the data-driven approach in the product development. Working with Python, ClickHouse, SQL and Grafana to collect and visualize the data. Visualized data about vehicle types and their popularity, which helped in making decisions about further development priorities.

Also responded to the enquiries on the corporate forum, collected feedback, managed requirements (both internal and external), builded roadmaps for the stream, defined priorities within the stream, created user stories and acceptance criteria.

EPAM Systems • Minsk, Belarus

Business Analyst (September 2019 – March 2020)

Certified UIPath Business Analyst. Implemented an OCR solution to the American manufacturing company. Small team of 5. Requirements gathering, tasks tracking, user stories and acceptance criteria creation, cross team communication. Managed project activities in Azure DevOps environment.

While also being part of the Intelligence Automation competency center, participated in 6 RFP processes by preparing documents with answers, updating competency center's capabilities decks, preparing case studies, requesting information about certifications, case studies from other locations.

EPAM Systems • Minsk, Belarus

Business Analyst (playing Proxy Product Owner role) (March 2018 – August 2019)

Being a part of a team of 20 dedicated to the development of the desktop application (events.epam.com), which is the most important app within the corporate Events Management Software Suite. Initially the project was Scrum-based but has gradually transformed into Kanban.

Documented requirements for the mobile check-in application for the Waterfall-based one-time project. *Notable accomplishments:*

- Balanced the workload of the team during the rapid growth of the development team.
- Got recognized by the organizers of the biggest event in the company's history (SEC 2018) for the provided assistance and solutions on the platform which fit the needs.
- Saved resources by suggesting solutions based on the current functionality.

EPAM Systems • Minsk, Belarus

Presales Analyst (Research Team) (December 2014 – March 2018)

Researched markets, companies, identified problems companies had, proposed solutions which could be suggested, scanned industry trends with focus on tech. Communicated with EPAM's VPs and Sales representatives as our customers. Prepared monthly newsletter covering clients in NA and EU regions.

Notable accomplishments:

• Drived an internal tool development handling Business Analyst role (requirements gathering, UI creation, communication, wiki-page creation with tool's capabilities description) which increased the team's productivity and dramatically reduced time needed for report preparation from 8 hours to 4.

EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS

BELARUSIAN STATE UNIVERSITY OF INFORMATICS AND RADIOELECTRONICS

Bachelor's Degree in Marketing, 2011 – 2015

Certification

IELTS 7.5 (C1 Advanced / Fluent English) • December 2020

Daily Used Tools

Microsoft Office Suite • Google Docs Suite • Miro • Figma • JIRA & Confluence suite